MARIELLE SEGARRA, HOST: Do you remember when we would go to that bar in Philly after work for happy hour? 你还记得以前我们下班后会去费城（Philly）那家酒吧参加 happy hour 吗？⭐ happy hour 欢乐时段（酒吧餐厅的折扣时段）｜go to a bar 去酒吧
JOE HERNANDEZ, BYLINE: Oh, big time. The cheap pizzas and the generous beer pours, yeah, I remember that. 当然记得，而且印象特别深。便宜的披萨，还有分量很足的啤酒，我当然记得。⭐ big time 当然，非常｜generous beer pours 啤酒倒得很足（餐饮常用表达）
SEGARRA: The happy hour deals were pretty key. I actually liked the pizza. Happy hour 的优惠真的很重要。而且我其实还挺喜欢那里的披萨。⭐ deal 优惠活动｜be key 非常重要
HERNANDEZ: Yeah, it was good at the time. 是啊，当时确实挺好吃的。⭐ at the time 当时
SEGARRA: I remember I would get a whole one for myself, and people would think that I had gotten it to share with the group, and then I would sort of take it to the side. 我记得我会给自己点一整个披萨，别人还以为我是点来跟大家一起分享的，然后我就会默默把它挪到旁边去。⭐ get a whole one 点一整个｜share with the group 和大家一起分享｜take it to the side 把它挪到一边
HERNANDEZ: Yeah, like, do some defensive maneuvers. 对，就像是在做一些防御动作一样。⭐ defensive maneuvers 防御动作（幽默表达）
SEGARRA: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Like, the arm around the plate. I remember people being like, you get really quiet when you eat. 对，对，就是把胳膊护在盘子周围。我记得别人还会说："你吃饭的时候怎么突然变得这么安静？"⭐ arm around the plate 用胳膊护住盘子｜get quiet 安静下来
SEGARRA: I'm like, yeah, I'm focused. 我就会说："对啊，我正专心吃呢。"⭐ be focused 专心、全神贯注
HERNANDEZ: Right. I don't want you interrupting me. 没错，我可不想别人打扰我吃饭。⭐ interrupt 打断、打扰
SEGARRA: All right. Well, you're listening to LIFE KIT. This is Marielle Segarra. I'm here with Joe Hernandez. We used to work together back at WHYY. We were both reporters at the time, right? 好的，欢迎收听《LIFE KIT》。我是 Marielle Segarra，今天和我一起的是 Joe Hernandez。我们以前都在 WHYY 工作，当时我们都是记者，对吧？⭐ used to work together 曾一起工作｜at the time 当时
SEGARRA: And, Joe, you have been reporting on this topic, actually, right? Like, on food and how much we pay for it, basically. Joe，其实你最近一直在报道这个话题，对吧？也就是关于食物，以及我们为食物花多少钱。⭐ report on 报道……｜basically 基本上、简单来说
HERNANDEZ: Right. Well, we started thinking about how everything is so expensive right now, and specifically food, how food prices are just going up. 没错。我们开始思考，现在几乎所有东西都变得很贵，尤其是食品价格，一直在上涨。⭐ food prices 食品价格｜go up 上涨（口语高频）
And, you know, we were thinking about sort of what are people feeling about this right now? 我们就在想，人们现在对这种情况到底是什么感受。⭐ what are people feeling about this 人们对此怎么看
What sorts of strategies are they using to deal with this moment when it feels like food has gotten much more expensive, but we all need to eat? 大家都在采用哪些办法来应对这个时期呢？毕竟食物越来越贵，但每个人都得吃饭。⭐ strategy 应对策略｜deal with 应对｜food has gotten much more expensive 食物贵了很多
And part of that was how to go out and not spend a ton of money because many of us don't want to cook every single meal of the day and every single day of the week, so we're going to go out sometimes. 其中一个问题就是，怎样才能外出吃饭却不用花太多钱。毕竟很多人都不想每天、每顿饭都自己做，所以偶尔还是会出去吃。⭐ spend a ton of money 花很多钱（口语）｜go out 外出吃饭｜every single 每一个、所有的（加强语气）
So how can you do that a little bit more affordably than you otherwise would? 那么，怎样才能让外出吃饭变得更省钱一点呢？⭐ affordably 负担得起地、经济实惠地
SEGARRA: Yeah, 'cause we know generally that eating at a restaurant or getting takeout is going to be more expensive than cooking at home. 是啊，因为大家都知道，在餐厅吃饭或者点外卖，通常都会比自己在家做饭更贵。⭐ get takeout 点外卖｜cook at home
But you can't give the advice never do it. 但你也不能直接建议大家永远别出去吃。⭐ give the advice 给建议
HERNANDEZ: Yeah, I think some people don't do it at all, but many people, myself included, will go out to a restaurant sometimes or get takeout. 是啊，有些人确实从来不出去吃，但很多人，包括我自己，还是会偶尔去餐厅或者点外卖。⭐ myself included 包括我自己（IELTS高频插入语）
And there are benefits to just being in a restaurant. 其实，仅仅待在一家餐厅里，本身也是有好处的。⭐ benefit to doing sth 做某事的好处
I talked to Hanna Garth about this. She's a Princeton University anthropology professor who does research on food access, specifically in Los Angeles. 我就这个问题采访了 Hanna Garth。她是普林斯顿大学的人类学教授，主要研究人们获取食物的情况，尤其关注洛杉矶地区。⭐ do research on 研究……｜food access 食物获取（社会学常用表达）｜specifically 尤其是
HANNA GARTH: For a lot of people, it's just about breaking from the routine and the monotony of eating at home. 对很多人来说，外出吃饭只是为了打破每天在家吃饭的固定模式和单调感。⭐ break from the routine 打破日常规律（雅思高频）｜monotony 单调、乏味（C1）
It's about alleviating that, the burden of the work of cooking a meal and cleaning up after the meal. 也是为了减轻做饭和饭后收拾的负担。⭐ alleviate 缓解、减轻（C1）｜the burden of ……的负担｜clean up after the meal 饭后收拾
HERNANDEZ: But there's also a social benefit here. 不过，外出吃饭还有一个社交层面的好处。⭐ social benefit 社交方面的益处
Restaurants are what's known as a third space, which is an area outside of our home or where we work where we interact with other people. 餐厅被称为 "第三空间（third space）"，也就是除了家庭和工作场所以外，人们能够与他人互动的地方。⭐ third space 第三空间（社会学概念）｜interact with 与……互动
And those casual interactions with strangers, with acquaintances, they can actually boost our mental health a little bit. 而这些和陌生人、熟人的随意交流，其实能够在一定程度上提升我们的心理健康。⭐ casual interactions 随意交流｜acquaintance 熟人｜boost 提升
SEGARRA: Yeah, I definitely found that when we were working together. 是的，我和你一起工作的时候，确实有这种感觉。⭐ definitely 确实
It was like, you'd have such a long day, and if every day I just had to go home and kind of cook by myself, I think that can get pretty lonely. 工作一天已经够累了，如果每天都只能回家一个人做饭，我觉得那样真的会很孤独。⭐ have a long day 忙碌/辛苦的一天｜get lonely 变得孤单
HERNANDEZ: Yeah, and just even small talk with a stranger or talking with your waiter or turning to the table next to you and asking them how the dessert was, you know, those kinds of small interactions can just make us feel better and make us feel like part of a community. 没错，哪怕只是和陌生人闲聊两句、跟服务员说说话，或者转身问隔壁桌甜点怎么样，这些小小的互动都会让我们心情更好，也让我们觉得自己是社区的一部分。⭐ small talk 寒暄、闲聊（雅思高频）｜turn to 转向……｜part of a community 社区的一员
SEGARRA: On this episode of LIFE KIT, how to eat out on a budget. 本期《LIFE KIT》，我们来聊聊如何省钱下馆子。⭐ eat out on a budget 花小钱外出吃饭（非常值得积累）
All right, Joe, so what is your first tip? 好，Joe，第一个建议是什么？
HERNANDEZ: So the first tip that I heard from multiple experts is think about why you want to eat out in the first place. 很多专家给出的第一个建议都是，先想清楚自己为什么要出去吃饭。⭐ in the first place 首先；归根结底（口语高频）
That's what Kimberly Palmer of NerdWallet told me. 这是 NerdWallet 的 Kimberly Palmer 告诉我的。
Are you going to try, like, a buzzy new restaurant or are you just out to socialize with your friends or your family members? 你是想去打卡一家最近很火的餐厅，还是只是想和朋友、家人聚一聚？⭐ buzzy 很火、很受关注（口语）｜socialize with 与……社交
Because if it's just to socialize, you get some more flexibility in choosing how you eventually decide to eat out. 如果只是为了社交，那你在选择去哪里、怎么吃这件事上，其实就有更多灵活性。⭐ flexibility 灵活性
KIMBERLY PALMER: You might be getting just as much value and enjoyment by going out for a less expensive pizza than a nicer restaurant. 与其去一家高档餐厅，去吃一顿便宜一点的披萨，也许同样能获得一样多的价值和快乐。⭐ get value from 从……获得价值｜less expensive 更便宜的
So just putting some time into thinking about why you're going out, what you want to get out of it, that can help guide your decisions. 所以，花点时间想想自己为什么要出去吃，以及希望得到什么，这会帮助你做出更好的决定。⭐ put time into 花时间做……｜get out of 从……获得｜guide your decisions
HERNANDEZ: And your decision might be to not go out at all. 甚至你的决定可能就是干脆不出去吃。⭐ not…at all 根本不
Kimberly says she sometimes just orders catering trays from a favorite local spot and has people over to her house. Kimberly 说，她有时会直接从一家自己喜欢的本地餐厅订一大盘聚餐套餐，然后邀请朋友来家里。⭐ catering tray 聚餐大份餐｜local spot 本地餐馆（口语）｜have people over 邀请朋友来家里（★★★★★）
And then any leftovers that come from that, she just has for lunch the next day. 剩下来的食物，她第二天就当午饭吃。⭐ leftovers 剩饭剩菜（高频）｜have…for lunch 当午饭吃
But if you are going to go out, she and others say, first figure out that why, what you want to get out of the experience, and then give yourself a budget. 但如果你确实打算出去吃，她和其他专家都建议，先弄清楚自己的目的，再给自己设定一个预算。⭐ figure out 搞清楚（★★★★★）｜give yourself a budget 给自己设定预算
SEGARRA: Is there an amount that the experts you spoke to recommend for how much we should budget for eating out? 那你采访的这些专家，有没有建议我们每个月应该拿多少钱作为外出吃饭的预算呢？⭐ budget for 为……做预算
HERNANDEZ: Not exactly. 倒也没有一个固定的数字。
I mean, I think it's going to be different for everybody, but there are some strategies for how you could think about it. 我觉得每个人情况都不一样，不过他们确实提供了一些制定预算的方法。⭐ strategy 方法、策略
So one is to look back at your past spending habits and see how much you've been spending on food outside of your home, and then that would be your starting point if you want to save money from there. 其中一个方法就是回顾一下自己过去的消费习惯，看看在外面吃饭花了多少钱，这可以作为你之后省钱的起点。⭐ look back at 回顾｜spending habits 消费习惯｜starting point 起点
And that might also highlight some patterns for you. 这样也能帮助你发现一些消费规律。⭐ highlight 显现、突出｜pattern 规律
So if you've been buying a salad or something every day at work, you could start packing your lunch more often. 比如，如果你每天上班都会买一份沙拉，那你可以开始更频繁地自己带午饭。⭐ pack your lunch 自带午餐（★★★★★）
(Qmusic) (SOUNDBITE OF MUSIC) （音乐）
SEGARRA: I always end up eating these slop bowls near our office when I forget to pack my lunch, and they're just like, they're at least $15, and I never like them. 我每次忘记带午饭的时候，最后都会去办公室附近吃那种"大杂烩饭碗（slop bowls）"，一份至少要15美元，而且我其实从来都不喜欢吃。⭐ end up doing 最终做了……（★★★★★）｜pack my lunch 自带午饭｜at least 至少
And it's just, it's too much dressing, a lot of the time. 很多时候，里面的沙拉酱都放得太多了。⭐ dressing （沙拉）酱汁
So by the time you get halfway through the bowl, you're like, I don't want to eat any of the rest of this, you know? 所以等吃到一半的时候，你就会觉得："剩下的我一点都不想吃了。"⭐ halfway through 吃到一半｜the rest of 剩下的……
HERNANDEZ: Yep. 没错。
SEGARRA: And that for me is really just about the convenience. 对我来说，这完全就是图方便。⭐ it's about convenience 图方便（★★★★★）
It's like, I didn't have time to throw together lunch that day, which, I mean, it is its own reason to eat out, right? 因为那天没时间随便准备一份午饭，而这本身就是外出吃饭的一个理由，不是吗？⭐ throw together 匆忙拼凑、随便准备（★★★★★）｜its own reason 本身就是理由
You don't have to cook or plan ahead for that meal. 你不用做饭，也不用提前准备那顿饭。⭐ plan ahead 提前规划（★★★★★）
HERNANDEZ: Yeah. And if it's worth it to you to spend that money and save yourself the time, then it's worth it. 是啊，如果对你来说，多花点钱能够节省时间，而且你觉得值得，那它就是值得的。⭐ be worth it 值得（★★★★★）