MARIELLE SEGARRA, HOST: Do you remember when we would go to that bar in Philly after work for happy hour? 你还记得以前我们下班后会去费城（Philly）那家酒吧参加 happy hour 吗？⭐ happy hour 欢乐时段（酒吧餐厅的折扣时段）｜go to a bar 去酒吧
JOE HERNANDEZ, BYLINE: Oh, big time. The cheap pizzas and the generous beer pours, yeah, I remember that. 当然记得，而且印象特别深。便宜的披萨，还有分量很足的啤酒，我当然记得。⭐ big time 当然，非常｜generous beer pours 啤酒倒得很足（餐饮常用表达）
SEGARRA: The happy hour deals were pretty key. I actually liked the pizza. Happy hour 的优惠真的很重要。而且我其实还挺喜欢那里的披萨。⭐ deal 优惠活动｜be key 非常重要
HERNANDEZ: Yeah, it was good at the time. 是啊，当时确实挺好吃的。⭐ at the time 当时
SEGARRA: I remember I would get a whole one for myself, and people would think that I had gotten it to share with the group, and then I would sort of take it to the side. 我记得我会给自己点一整个披萨，别人还以为我是点来跟大家一起分享的，然后我就会默默把它挪到旁边去。⭐ get a whole one 点一整个｜share with the group 和大家一起分享｜take it to the side 把它挪到一边
HERNANDEZ: Yeah, like, do some defensive maneuvers. 对，就像是在做一些防御动作一样。⭐ defensive maneuvers 防御动作（幽默表达）
SEGARRA: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Like, the arm around the plate. I remember people being like, you get really quiet when you eat. 对，对，就是把胳膊护在盘子周围。我记得别人还会说："你吃饭的时候怎么突然变得这么安静？"⭐ arm around the plate 用胳膊护住盘子｜get quiet 安静下来
SEGARRA: I'm like, yeah, I'm focused. 我就会说："对啊，我正专心吃呢。"⭐ be focused 专心、全神贯注
HERNANDEZ: Right. I don't want you interrupting me. 没错，我可不想别人打扰我吃饭。⭐ interrupt 打断、打扰
SEGARRA: All right. Well, you're listening to LIFE KIT. This is Marielle Segarra. I'm here with Joe Hernandez. We used to work together back at WHYY. We were both reporters at the time, right? 好的，欢迎收听《LIFE KIT》。我是 Marielle Segarra，今天和我一起的是 Joe Hernandez。我们以前都在 WHYY 工作，当时我们都是记者，对吧？⭐ used to work together 曾一起工作｜at the time 当时
SEGARRA: And, Joe, you have been reporting on this topic, actually, right? Like, on food and how much we pay for it, basically. Joe，其实你最近一直在报道这个话题，对吧？也就是关于食物，以及我们为食物花多少钱。⭐ report on 报道……｜basically 基本上、简单来说
HERNANDEZ: Right. Well, we started thinking about how everything is so expensive right now, and specifically food, how food prices are just going up. 没错。我们开始思考，现在几乎所有东西都变得很贵，尤其是食品价格，一直在上涨。⭐ food prices 食品价格｜go up 上涨（口语高频）
And, you know, we were thinking about sort of what are people feeling about this right now? 我们就在想，人们现在对这种情况到底是什么感受。⭐ what are people feeling about this 人们对此怎么看
What sorts of strategies are they using to deal with this moment when it feels like food has gotten much more expensive, but we all need to eat? 大家都在采用哪些办法来应对这个时期呢？毕竟食物越来越贵，但每个人都得吃饭。⭐ strategy 应对策略｜deal with 应对｜food has gotten much more expensive 食物贵了很多
And part of that was how to go out and not spend a ton of money because many of us don't want to cook every single meal of the day and every single day of the week, so we're going to go out sometimes. 其中一个问题就是，怎样才能外出吃饭却不用花太多钱。毕竟很多人都不想每天、每顿饭都自己做，所以偶尔还是会出去吃。⭐ spend a ton of money 花很多钱（口语）｜go out 外出吃饭｜every single 每一个、所有的（加强语气）
So how can you do that a little bit more affordably than you otherwise would? 那么，怎样才能让外出吃饭变得更省钱一点呢？⭐ affordably 负担得起地、经济实惠地
SEGARRA: Yeah, 'cause we know generally that eating at a restaurant or getting takeout is going to be more expensive than cooking at home. 是啊，因为大家都知道，在餐厅吃饭或者点外卖，通常都会比自己在家做饭更贵。⭐ get takeout 点外卖｜cook at home
But you can't give the advice never do it. 但你也不能直接建议大家永远别出去吃。⭐ give the advice 给建议
HERNANDEZ: Yeah, I think some people don't do it at all, but many people, myself included, will go out to a restaurant sometimes or get takeout. 是啊，有些人确实从来不出去吃，但很多人，包括我自己，还是会偶尔去餐厅或者点外卖。⭐ myself included 包括我自己（IELTS高频插入语）
And there are benefits to just being in a restaurant. 其实，仅仅待在一家餐厅里，本身也是有好处的。⭐ benefit to doing sth 做某事的好处
I talked to Hanna Garth about this. She's a Princeton University anthropology professor who does research on food access, specifically in Los Angeles. 我就这个问题采访了 Hanna Garth。她是普林斯顿大学的人类学教授，主要研究人们获取食物的情况，尤其关注洛杉矶地区。⭐ do research on 研究……｜food access 食物获取（社会学常用表达）｜specifically 尤其是
HANNA GARTH: For a lot of people, it's just about breaking from the routine and the monotony of eating at home. 对很多人来说，外出吃饭只是为了打破每天在家吃饭的固定模式和单调感。⭐ break from the routine 打破日常规律（雅思高频）｜monotony 单调、乏味（C1）
It's about alleviating that, the burden of the work of cooking a meal and cleaning up after the meal. 也是为了减轻做饭和饭后收拾的负担。⭐ alleviate 缓解、减轻（C1）｜the burden of ……的负担｜clean up after the meal 饭后收拾
HERNANDEZ: But there's also a social benefit here. 不过，外出吃饭还有一个社交层面的好处。⭐ social benefit 社交方面的益处
Restaurants are what's known as a third space, which is an area outside of our home or where we work where we interact with other people. 餐厅被称为 "第三空间（third space）"，也就是除了家庭和工作场所以外，人们能够与他人互动的地方。⭐ third space 第三空间（社会学概念）｜interact with 与……互动
And those casual interactions with strangers, with acquaintances, they can actually boost our mental health a little bit. 而这些和陌生人、熟人的随意交流，其实能够在一定程度上提升我们的心理健康。⭐ casual interactions 随意交流｜acquaintance 熟人｜boost 提升
SEGARRA: Yeah, I definitely found that when we were working together. 是的，我和你一起工作的时候，确实有这种感觉。⭐ definitely 确实
It was like, you'd have such a long day, and if every day I just had to go home and kind of cook by myself, I think that can get pretty lonely. 工作一天已经够累了，如果每天都只能回家一个人做饭，我觉得那样真的会很孤独。⭐ have a long day 忙碌/辛苦的一天｜get lonely 变得孤单
HERNANDEZ: Yeah, and just even small talk with a stranger or talking with your waiter or turning to the table next to you and asking them how the dessert was, you know, those kinds of small interactions can just make us feel better and make us feel like part of a community. 没错，哪怕只是和陌生人闲聊两句、跟服务员说说话，或者转身问隔壁桌甜点怎么样，这些小小的互动都会让我们心情更好，也让我们觉得自己是社区的一部分。⭐ small talk 寒暄、闲聊（雅思高频）｜turn to 转向……｜part of a community 社区的一员
SEGARRA: On this episode of LIFE KIT, how to eat out on a budget. 本期《LIFE KIT》，我们来聊聊如何省钱下馆子。⭐ eat out on a budget 花小钱外出吃饭（非常值得积累）
All right, Joe, so what is your first tip? 好，Joe，第一个建议是什么？
HERNANDEZ: So the first tip that I heard from multiple experts is think about why you want to eat out in the first place. 很多专家给出的第一个建议都是，先想清楚自己为什么要出去吃饭。⭐ in the first place 首先；归根结底（口语高频）
That's what Kimberly Palmer of NerdWallet told me. 这是 NerdWallet 的 Kimberly Palmer 告诉我的。
Are you going to try, like, a buzzy new restaurant or are you just out to socialize with your friends or your family members? 你是想去打卡一家最近很火的餐厅，还是只是想和朋友、家人聚一聚？⭐ buzzy 很火、很受关注（口语）｜socialize with 与……社交
Because if it's just to socialize, you get some more flexibility in choosing how you eventually decide to eat out. 如果只是为了社交，那你在选择去哪里、怎么吃这件事上，其实就有更多灵活性。⭐ flexibility 灵活性
KIMBERLY PALMER: You might be getting just as much value and enjoyment by going out for a less expensive pizza than a nicer restaurant. 与其去一家高档餐厅，去吃一顿便宜一点的披萨，也许同样能获得一样多的价值和快乐。⭐ get value from 从……获得价值｜less expensive 更便宜的
So just putting some time into thinking about why you're going out, what you want to get out of it, that can help guide your decisions. 所以，花点时间想想自己为什么要出去吃，以及希望得到什么，这会帮助你做出更好的决定。⭐ put time into 花时间做……｜get out of 从……获得｜guide your decisions
HERNANDEZ: And your decision might be to not go out at all. 甚至你的决定可能就是干脆不出去吃。⭐ not…at all 根本不
Kimberly says she sometimes just orders catering trays from a favorite local spot and has people over to her house. Kimberly 说，她有时会直接从一家自己喜欢的本地餐厅订一大盘聚餐套餐，然后邀请朋友来家里。⭐ catering tray 聚餐大份餐｜local spot 本地餐馆（口语）｜have people over 邀请朋友来家里（★★★★★）
And then any leftovers that come from that, she just has for lunch the next day. 剩下来的食物，她第二天就当午饭吃。⭐ leftovers 剩饭剩菜（高频）｜have…for lunch 当午饭吃
But if you are going to go out, she and others say, first figure out that why, what you want to get out of the experience, and then give yourself a budget. 但如果你确实打算出去吃，她和其他专家都建议，先弄清楚自己的目的，再给自己设定一个预算。⭐ figure out 搞清楚（★★★★★）｜give yourself a budget 给自己设定预算
SEGARRA: Is there an amount that the experts you spoke to recommend for how much we should budget for eating out? 那你采访的这些专家，有没有建议我们每个月应该拿多少钱作为外出吃饭的预算呢？⭐ budget for 为……做预算
HERNANDEZ: Not exactly. 倒也没有一个固定的数字。
I mean, I think it's going to be different for everybody, but there are some strategies for how you could think about it. 我觉得每个人情况都不一样，不过他们确实提供了一些制定预算的方法。⭐ strategy 方法、策略
So one is to look back at your past spending habits and see how much you've been spending on food outside of your home, and then that would be your starting point if you want to save money from there. 其中一个方法就是回顾一下自己过去的消费习惯，看看在外面吃饭花了多少钱，这可以作为你之后省钱的起点。⭐ look back at 回顾｜spending habits 消费习惯｜starting point 起点
And that might also highlight some patterns for you. 这样也能帮助你发现一些消费规律。⭐ highlight 显现、突出｜pattern 规律
So if you've been buying a salad or something every day at work, you could start packing your lunch more often. 比如，如果你每天上班都会买一份沙拉，那你可以开始更频繁地自己带午饭。⭐ pack your lunch 自带午餐（★★★★★）
SEGARRA: I always end up eating these slop bowls near our office when I forget to pack my lunch, and they're just like, they're at least $15, and I never like them. 我每次忘记带午饭的时候，最后都会去办公室附近吃那种"大杂烩饭碗（slop bowls）"，一份至少要15美元，而且我其实从来都不喜欢吃。⭐ end up doing 最终做了……（★★★★★）｜pack my lunch 自带午饭｜at least 至少
And it's just, it's too much dressing, a lot of the time. 很多时候，里面的沙拉酱都放得太多了。⭐ dressing （沙拉）酱汁
So by the time you get halfway through the bowl, you're like, I don't want to eat any of the rest of this, you know? 所以等吃到一半的时候，你就会觉得："剩下的我一点都不想吃了。"⭐ halfway through 吃到一半｜the rest of 剩下的……
HERNANDEZ: Yep. 没错。
SEGARRA: And that for me is really just about the convenience. 对我来说，这完全就是图方便。⭐ it's about convenience 图方便（★★★★★）
It's like, I didn't have time to throw together lunch that day, which, I mean, it is its own reason to eat out, right? 因为那天没时间随便准备一份午饭，而这本身就是外出吃饭的一个理由，不是吗？⭐ throw together 匆忙拼凑、随便准备（★★★★★）｜its own reason 本身就是理由
You don't have to cook or plan ahead for that meal. 你不用做饭，也不用提前准备那顿饭。⭐ plan ahead 提前规划（★★★★★）
HERNANDEZ: Yeah. And if it's worth it to you to spend that money and save yourself the time, then it's worth it. 是啊，如果对你来说，多花点钱能够节省时间，而且你觉得值得，那它就是值得的。⭐ be worth it 值得（★★★★★）
But if you would rather not be spending that money and you just do it because you don't have any lunch prepared for that day, all the experts I spoke to said one of the most important things that you can do is plan ahead. 但如果你其实并不想花这笔钱，只是因为那天没有准备午饭，那么所有专家都说，最重要的一件事就是提前规划。⭐ would rather not 宁愿不……｜have lunch prepared 把午饭准备好｜plan ahead
And in this case, that could mean, like, making a big batch of lunches over the weekend and then bringing it with you to work. 比如，你可以周末一次性做好很多份午饭，然后每天带去上班。⭐ a big batch of 一大批、一大份（★★★★★）｜bring it with you 带着它
SEGARRA: And then if you do that, I mean, you're saving yourself more of your eating-out budget for stuff that you'd actually enjoy. 这样一来，你就能把更多外出吃饭的预算留给那些真正值得享受的餐厅。⭐ save…for 留给……｜actually enjoy
HERNANDEZ: Right. You can kind of pick and choose rather than be limited because you ended up spending $45 the previous week getting those lunches that you just didn't pack. 没错。这样你就可以自由选择，而不是因为上一周花了45美元买那些本来可以自己带的午饭，结果预算受限。⭐ pick and choose 自由挑选（★★★★★）｜be limited 受到限制｜end up doing
And then there's kind of like the question of where is that eating-out budget? 另外，还有一个问题，就是这笔外出吃饭的预算到底应该放在哪一类支出里。⭐ budget 预算
Because one of the experts I spoke to, financial counselor Lindsay Plumb, says she keeps her eating-out budget separate from her grocery budget. 因为我采访的一位专家，理财顾问 Lindsay Plumb 说，她会把外出吃饭预算和买菜预算完全分开。⭐ keep…separate from… 把……和……分开（★★★★★）
So the thinking there is that your grocery budget is kind of its own thing, and that's just for groceries. 她的理念是，买菜预算就是买菜预算，只能用于购买食材。⭐ its own thing 独立的一部分（口语）
And separating it from your eating-out money and whatever other parts of your budget you have means you're not dipping into your grocery money for expensive restaurants or other costs that are just for fun. 把它和外出吃饭的钱分开，就意味着你不会为了去高档餐厅或者其他娱乐消费，而动用买菜的钱。⭐ dip into 动用（存款/预算）（★★★★★）｜for fun 娱乐用途
LINDSAY PLUMB: My grocery money does not touch, I call it our spend-with-joy money. 我的买菜预算绝不会和我所谓的"快乐消费基金"混在一起。⭐ spend-with-joy money 快乐消费预算（值得借鉴）
The spend-with-joy money I get to spend truly with joy. 这笔钱，我可以真正毫无负担地花。⭐ with joy 开心地
You know, not worrying whether or not I can pay my mortgage or buy the groceries or if the kids need cleats, because we have a sports account, and that's the one that's going to pay for the cleats. 这样我就不用担心房贷、买菜的钱，或者孩子需要买足球鞋，因为这些都有各自独立的预算。⭐ mortgage 房贷｜cleats （足球等运动）钉鞋
Our grocery account is going to pay for our groceries. 买菜的钱，就专门用来买菜。
HERNANDEZ: And then there are a few kind of other things that the personal finance experts told me about budgeting. 另外，理财专家还给了我一些关于预算的小建议。⭐ personal finance 个人理财
Sometimes restaurants will have these loyalty programs that offer discounts or free items, so you could sign up for those. 有些餐厅会推出会员积分计划，提供折扣或者免费赠品，所以可以注册参加。⭐ loyalty program 会员积分计划（★★★★★）｜sign up for 注册参加
And then some credit card rewards programs also give customers extra points for spending money in restaurants. 另外，有些信用卡积分计划也会为餐厅消费提供额外积分。⭐ reward program 积分奖励计划｜extra points
SEGARRA: I think one problem that people often have when they do go to restaurants is that they overspend. 我觉得很多人去餐厅都会遇到一个问题，就是容易花超预算。⭐ overspend 超支（★★★★★）
What can you do to avoid that? 那怎样才能避免这种情况呢？⭐ avoid
HERNANDEZ: So one more thing before you even show up is to look at the menu. 还有一个建议，就是在去餐厅之前，先看看菜单。⭐ show up 到场（★★★★★）
Because the experts that I spoke to, they all said preparation is key to saving money. 因为我采访的所有专家都认为，提前准备是省钱的关键。⭐ preparation is key 准备是关键（★★★★★）
If you look at the menu ahead of time, you can kind of come up with a game plan of what you might want to order a little bit better. 如果提前看看菜单，你就可以提前想好自己准备点什么。⭐ ahead of time 提前（★★★★★）｜come up with 想出｜game plan 行动计划（口语）
You're not under pressure to do it when the waiter is standing right next to you, waiting for you to make a decision about whatever it is that you want. 这样就不用等服务员站在旁边的时候，匆匆忙忙地做决定。⭐ under pressure 有压力｜make a decision
SEGARRA: I feel like I do that anyway, just because I'm always super hungry. 我觉得我本来就会这么做，因为我总是饿得不行。⭐ I feel like… 我觉得……（超高频口语）｜super hungry 饿坏了；特别饿
SEGARRA: I'm trying to game plan, like, OK, we're going to get in, and I know what I want immediately. I don't have to - the waiter doesn't even have to hand me a menu. And then I'm like, is it ready yet? Is it ready? 我会提前做好计划，比如想着："好，我们一进去，我马上就知道自己要点什么。" 服务员甚至都不用把菜单递给我。然后我就一直在想："做好了吗？好了没？"⭐ game plan 提前制定计划；谋划（⭐⭐⭐⭐⭐ 非常地道）｜get in 进去（餐厅）｜hand sb a menu 把菜单递给某人
HERNANDEZ: Yeah (laughter). Right. And that's another thing. Like, showing up too hungry, you might order too much, you know. 哈哈，对啊。而且这也是一个问题。如果你到餐厅的时候已经饿得不行，很可能就会点太多。⭐ show up 到达；出现（高频 phrasal verb）｜order too much 点太多
HERNANDEZ: Your stomach might get ahead of your brain a little bit there. 那种情况下，你的胃可能会跑在脑子前面，让你失去理智地点餐。⭐ get ahead of 跑在……前面（⭐⭐⭐⭐⭐ 非常形象的表达）
SEGARRA: I've done that. 我确实干过这种事。⭐ I've done that. 我也这样过。（万能共鸣句）
HERNANDEZ: Some other tips, like sharing plates to save money or skipping drinks or even using the time of day to your advantage. Like, food deals tend to be a little bit cheaper during happy hours, for example. 还有一些建议，比如大家一起分着吃来省钱，或者不点饮料，又或者利用不同时间段的优惠。比如 Happy Hour 的餐饮优惠通常会便宜一些。⭐ share plates 分着吃（餐厅口语）｜skip drinks 不点饮料｜use… to your advantage 利用……为自己谋利（⭐⭐⭐⭐⭐ C1）｜food deals 餐饮优惠
SEGARRA: I find that sometimes it can cost more if I want to eat healthy when I'm eating out. I wonder, what tips did the experts have for dining out on a budget and also trying to eat healthy food? 我发现，有时候如果我想在外面吃得健康一点，反而会更贵。我很好奇，专家们对于既想省钱又想吃得健康有什么建议？⭐ eat healthy 吃得健康｜dine out on a budget 花有限预算外出吃饭（非常值得积累）
HERNANDEZ: Right. And there are ways to do this. So registered dietitian Amy Lawson told me that she encourages people to build their restaurant meals around protein and fiber. Those are the things that will kind of keep you full. 当然有办法。注册营养师 Amy Lawson 告诉我，她建议大家点餐时以蛋白质和膳食纤维为核心（build… around），因为这些食物更有饱腹感。⭐ registered dietitian 注册营养师｜build… around… 围绕……来安排（⭐⭐⭐⭐⭐ 很好迁移）｜protein and fiber 蛋白质和膳食纤维｜keep you full 让你更有饱腹感
And one way to do that is what she calls the balanced plate. 其中一个方法就是她所说的"均衡餐盘（balanced plate）"。⭐ balanced plate 均衡餐盘
Half the plate is non-starchy vegetables, a quarter is protein, and a quarter is complex carbs. 餐盘的一半应该是非淀粉类蔬菜，四分之一是蛋白质，另外四分之一是复合碳水。⭐ non-starchy vegetables 非淀粉类蔬菜｜complex carbs 复合碳水（complex carbohydrates）
And some cuisines, like Mediterranean, might make that easier than others. 有些菜系，比如地中海饮食，就更容易做到这一点。⭐ cuisine 菜系（B2）｜Mediterranean cuisine 地中海饮食
And it can be hard to actually get that balance if you're ordering something like a soup or a chili, where you don't really have control over that ratio, like a half to a quarter to a quarter, just making sure you're hitting all those categories of non-starchy vegetables, protein and complex carbs will help you. 不过，如果你点的是汤或者辣炖菜这类食物，就很难真正做到这种比例，因为你没法控制各种食材的占比。不过，只要确保这一餐包含了非淀粉类蔬菜、蛋白质和复合碳水这几个类别，就已经很不错了。⭐ have control over 控制；掌握（高频）｜ratio 比例（B2）｜hit all the categories 覆盖所有类别（很自然）
She says the key to making this possible - same thing with keeping track of your spending - is preparing ahead of time, reading the menu ahead of time and then making that plan. 她认为，实现这一点的关键，和控制消费其实一样，就是提前准备（prepare ahead of time），提前看菜单，然后提前做好决定。⭐ the key to… ……的关键（万能句型）｜keep track of 跟踪；记录（⭐⭐⭐⭐⭐ 雅思高频）｜prepare ahead of time 提前准备
AMY LAWSON: Especially when we go to a restaurant, and we get there, and we are really hungry - our hunger hormones are really loud, and they are telling us, I want - give me all the carbohydrates, give me the simple things, give me the quickest source of fuel. 尤其是当我们到了餐厅，已经非常饿的时候，饥饿激素（hunger hormones）会变得特别活跃，它们仿佛一直在对我们喊："我要碳水！我要最简单的食物！我要最快能提供能量的东西！"⭐ hunger hormones 饥饿激素｜the quickest source of fuel 最快的能量来源
So it can kind of muddle in our brain what we - our choices in terms of making the healthiest choice. 所以，它会让我们的大脑变得有点混乱，影响我们做出最健康的选择。⭐ muddle 搞乱；扰乱（C1）｜make the healthiest choice 做出最健康的选择
SEGARRA: Yeah. Yeah, I feel that for sure. It can be hard if you are ordering an entree, because they just plate it the way they plate it, and they like give you the amount of protein or rice or whatever… 是啊，我太有共鸣了。如果你点的是一份主菜，其实很难控制，因为餐厅就是按照他们自己的方式摆盘，给你多少肉、多少米饭，基本都是固定好的。⭐ I feel that. 我太有同感了。（⭐⭐⭐⭐⭐ 超自然）｜plate (v.) 摆盘；装盘
SEGARRA: …That they're going to give you. Although, I guess you can start to notice patterns, like, in the places you go and maybe just get, like, a protein-heavy appetizer or something. ……他们给多少就是多少。不过，我觉得你也可以慢慢总结规律，比如去熟悉的餐厅时，可以只点一份高蛋白前菜（protein-heavy appetizer）之类的。⭐ notice patterns 发现规律（很好迁移）｜protein-heavy appetizer 高蛋白前菜
HERNANDEZ: Right. And also, I mean, for me, if a plate of food comes out, it's going to be hard for me to, like, not eat that plate of food. 没错。而且对我来说，只要一整盘食物端上来了，我真的很难忍住不把它吃完。⭐ comes out （菜）端上来（餐厅高频）｜it's hard not to… 很难不……
But one of her tips is you can get a to-go box right when your food comes out and put half of it in the to-go box. 不过，她有一个建议是：菜一端上来，就马上要一个打包盒，把一半食物先装进去。⭐ to-go box 打包盒（美式）｜right when… 一……就……（高频）
And that will kind of control how much you're going to eat while you're sitting there. 这样一来，就能控制自己当场吃掉多少。⭐ control how much… 控制……的量（万能搭配）
And by the way, there's a couple other small tips that Lawson suggested, such as you can ask to customize things. You could get protein from chicken or beans rather than steak, for example. And then if you skip the sugary drinks altogether, you're going to save yourself money, and it will be healthier. 顺便提一句，Lawson 还提出了几个小建议。比如，你可以要求定制（customize）餐点。举个例子，你可以选择鸡肉或豆类作为蛋白质来源，而不是牛排。如果你完全不喝（skip… altogether）含糖饮料，不仅能省钱，也会更健康。⭐ by the way 顺便说一句（高频口语）｜customize 定制；按需求调整（B2）｜rather than 而不是（高频替换 instead of）｜skip… altogether 干脆不……；完全省掉……
(QSponsor/Ad) (SOUNDBITE OF MUSIC) （音乐）
SEGARRA: OK. Well, let's talk about takeout now. It can be so expensive. So how do you save money on this? 好，我们来聊聊外卖。它真的很贵。那么，怎样才能在点外卖时省钱呢？⭐ takeout 外卖（美式）｜save money on sth 在某方面省钱
HERNANDEZ: I mean, one of the simplest ways to save on takeout is to pick up your order yourself if you can do that. 其实，点外卖最简单的省钱方法之一，就是如果可以的话，自己去取餐（pick up your order）。⭐ pick up your order 自取订单（超高频）