"Let me walk you through a really practical framework I just picked up—the 3-2-1 method—using sunscreen as a case study.
The one core thing you absolutely need to nail about sunscreen isn't the SPF number; it's about applying it generously enough to actually get the protection.
When it comes to formulations, you're essentially looking at two distinct camps.
The first is the classic cream or lotion, which gives you precise coverage.
The second is the spray version, which is a lifesaver for quick reapplication, especially if you're heading for a swim or facing a scorching UV index outdoors.
As for the three actionable steps to find your perfect match:
First, know your skin type—oily, dry, or normal—because that dictates the base.
Second, don't just chase cult favorites like Lancôme, which come with a hefty price tag; take time to explore drugstore alternatives that offer better bang for your buck.
Third, before you rush to place an online order,
consider dropping by a physical store so you can get your hands on it immediately and skip the waiting game.