There's nothing to tell. It's just some guy I work with.
Come on. You're going out with the guy. There's got to be something wrong with him.
So, does he have a hump? A hump and a hairpiece?
Wait, does he eat chalk?
Just because I don't want her to go through what I went through with Carol.
Okay, everybody relax.
This is not even a date.
It's just two people going out to dinner and not having sex.
Sounds like a date to me.
All of a sudden, the phone starts to ring.
And it turns out it's my mother.
Which is very, very weird because she never calls me.
This guy says, "Hello, I want to kill myself."
I just feel like someone reached down my throat, grabbed my small intestine, pulled it out of my mouth and tied it around my neck.
Cookie? Cookie?
Carol moved her stuff out today. Carol
Stop cleansing my aura.
Don't just leave my aura alone, okay?
To hell with her.
No, okay? Why does everyone keep fixating on that?
Sometimes I wish I was a lesbian. Did I say that out loud?
All right, Ross, look, you're feeling a lot of pain right now. You're angry. You're hurting.
Can I tell you what the answer is? Strip joints.
Come on, you're single. Have some hormones.
See, but I don't want to be single, okay?
Rachel? Oh, God, Monica, hi. Thank God. Rachel？
I just went to your building, and you weren't there. And then this guy with a big hammer said that you might be here, and you are. You are.
Can I get you some coffee?
Decaf.
Okay, everybody, this is Rachel, another Lincoln High survivor.
So you want to tell us now, or are we waiting for four wet bridesmaids?
I was in this room where we were keeping all the presents, and I was looking at this gravy boat, this really gorgeous Limoges gravy boat.
When all of a sudden, sweet and low, I realized, I realized that I was more turned on by this gravy boat than by Barry.
And then I got really freaked out, and that's when it hit me, how much Barry looks like Mr. Potato Head.
You know, I mean, I always knew he looked familiar, but…
I just had to get out of there, and I started wondering, why am I doing this, and who am I doing this for?
So anyway, I just didn't know where to go, and I know that you and I have kind of drifted apart, but you're the only person I knew who lived here in the city.
Who wasn't invited to the wedding.
Oh, I was kind of hoping that wouldn't be an issue.
I'm guessing that he bought her the big pipe organ, and she's really not happy about it.
Ooh, she should not be wearing those pants.
I say push her down the stairs.
It's a metaphor, Daddy.
You can see where he'd have trouble.
Well, I guess we've established she's staying here with Monica.
Okay, just breathe, that's it.
Just try to think of nice, calm things.
Raindrops on roses… I'm all better now. （
This is probably for the best, you know?
Independence, taking control of your life.
And hey, you need anything, you can always come to Joey.
Me and Chandler live right across the hall.
And he's away a lot.
Joey, stop hitting on her. It's her wedding day. Joey，
What, like there's a rule or something?
Please don't do that again. It's a horrible sound.
Buzz him in.
Who's Paul? Paul the wine guy, Paul? Paul
Ooh, this is a Dear Diary moment.
Paul the wine guy. I'm sorry, I didn't catch your name. Paul, was it? Paul，
Okay, sit down. Two seconds.
Ooh, I just pulled out four eyelashes. That can't be good.
So, Rachel, what are you, uh, what are you up to tonight? Rachel，
Well, I was kind of supposed to be headed for Aruba on my honeymoon, so nothing.
Right, you're not even getting your honeymoon.
No, no, although Aruba, this time of year, talk about your… big lizards.
Anyway, if you don't feel like being alone tonight, Joey and Chandler are coming over to help me put together my new furniture.
Well, actually, thanks, but I think I'm just gonna hang out here tonight. It's been a long day.
Oh, sure, okay, sure. Hey, Pheebs, you want to help?
Oh, I wish I could, but I don't want to.
I'm supposed to attach a brackety thing to the side things using a bunch of these little worm guys.
I have no brackety thing, I see no worm guys whatsoever, and I cannot feel my legs.
What's this? I have no idea.
Done with the book, David!
This was Carol's favorite beer. She always drank it out of the can. I should have known.
She got the furniture, the stereo, the good TV. What did you get? You guys.
Oh, God. You got screwed.
I know, I know, I'm such an idiot.
I guess I should have caught on when she started going to the dentist four and five times a week.
I mean, how clean can teeth get?
My brother's going through that right now.
He's such a mess.
How did you get through it?
He might try accidentally breaking something valuable of hers.
Say, her…
Leg?
That's one way of going through it, yeah. Me, I went for the watch.
You actually broke her watch?
Barry, I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. I know you probably think this is all about what I said the other night about you making love with your socks on, but it isn't. Barry，
It isn't. It's about me, and I just… Bye, machine.
Cut me off again. Anyway…
You know what the scariest part is? What if there's only one woman for everybody, you know?
Unfortunately, in my case, there was only one woman for her.
That's like saying there's only one flavor of ice cream for you.
Let me tell you something, Ross. There's lots of flavors out there. Ross，
There's Rocky Road and cookie dough and, bing, cherry vanilla.
You can get them with jimmies or nuts. Or whipped cream.
This is the best thing that ever happened to you.
You got married. You were like, what, eight?
Welcome back to the world. Grab a spoon.
I honestly don't know if I'm hungry or horny.
You can stay out of my freezer.
Ever since she walked out on me, I…
What? What, what? You want to spell it out with noodles?
No, it's more of a fifth date kind of revelation.
Oh, so there's gonna be a fifth date?
Isn't there?
Yeah, yeah, I think there is. What were you gonna say?
Well, ever since she left me, I haven't been able to perform sexually.
I'm so sorry. It's okay. I know being spit on is probably not what you need right now.
Wow. I'm glad you've smashed your watch.
So you still think you might want that fifth date?
I, Joni, take you, Charles, as my lawful husband.
Oh, see? But Joni loved Charlie. That's the difference.
Grab a spoon.
Do you know how long it's been since I've grabbed a spoon?
Do the words, Billy, don't be a hero, mean anything to you? "Billy，
You know, here's the thing.
Even if I could get it together enough day and all time to ask a woman out, who am I gonna ask?
I've never made coffee before in my entire life.
That is amazing.
Congratulations.
Why are you on a roll if you feel like you've got to make, like, a Western omelet or something?
Although, actually, I'm really not that hungry this morning.
That wasn't a real date. What the hell do you do on a real date?
Shut up and put my table back. Okay.
All right, kids, I gotta get to work. If I don't input those numbers, doesn't make much of a difference.
So, like, you guys all have jobs? Yeah, we all have jobs. See, that's how we buy stuff.
Yeah, I'm an actor. Wow. But I've seen you in anything?
Oh, I doubt it. Mostly regional work.
Okay, unless you happen to catch the Wee Ones production of Pinocchio.
Look, Geppetto, I'm a real live boy. I will not take this abuse. Hey, Ryan, I'm sorry.
Once I was a wooden boy.
I am just going to get up, go to work, and not think about him all day. Or else I'm just going to get up and go to work.
Oh, I wish me luck. What for? I'm going to go get one of those job things.
Hey, Monica. Brandy, welcome back. How was Florida?
You know, before me, there was no snapping this turtle for two years.
Of course it was a line.
I assume we're looking for an answer more sophisticated than to get you into bed.
Is it me? Is it like I have some sort of beacon that only dogs and men with severe emotional problems can hear?
Are you kidding? I'm trained for nothing. I was laughed at 12 interviews today.
And yet you're surprisingly upbeat.
Well, you would be too if you found Joan and David boots on sale, 50% off.
Oh, how well you know me.
They're my new I-don't-need-a-job, I-don't-need-my-parents, I've-got-great-boots boots.
How'd you pay for them?
A credit card.
And who pays for that?
Come on, you can't live off your parents your whole life.
I know that. That's why I was getting married.
Give her a break.
It's hard being on your own for the first time.
I was 14.
My mom had just killed herself and my stepdad was back in prison.
And I got here and I didn't know anybody.
And I ended up living with this albino guy who was, like, cleaning windshields outside Port Authority.
And then he killed himself.
And then I found aromatherapy.
So, believe me, I know exactly how you feel.
The word you're looking for is… anyway.
Cut, cut, cut…
Welcome to the real world! It sucks.
You're gonna love it.
You gonna crash on the couch?
No, no. I gotta go home sometime.
You just put it back where you found it.
Split it?
Okay. You know, you probably didn't know this, but back in high school, I had a, um… major crush on you.
I knew.
You did?
I always figured you just thought I was Monica's geeky older brother.
I did.
Oh.
Listen, do you think…
and try not to let my intense vulnerability become any kind of a factor here…
but do you think it would be okay if I asked you out sometime, maybe?
Yeah, maybe.
Okay. Okay, maybe I will.